Alright, let's continue from where we left off last class.
Let's optimize this method.
Now, while we've added a lock here in our method,
when you add items to the queue,
this part is locked,
but if two threads try to, um,
insert a task at the same time,
then we need to clarify what happens in our task queue,
as it might have additional insertions.
You're inserting some in the middle as well
So the two sounds overlap
It will get chaotic
That's why we need to wait for the background task
While it's playing the music
The new music playback
We need to wait for its background task to complete
How do we wait?
I'll just copy it over here
a method for waiting
click it
in the file, I add a method to wait for this background task to complete
such a method
then we write this method here
copy this and paste it here
it's quite simple
first, I acquire the lock
then we wait inside the lock, wait for what
Wait for this queue to be empty
and the last task has also been executed
If you just wait for the queue to be empty
there might still be a task executing, right?
So we should be more precise
just wait for it to be empty
or return when it equals zero
When we define it
we didn't set it to equal zero
So, we use its constructor here
We set it to zero
This means during initialization, we set it to zero
Then this way, it won’t cause a deadlock
Otherwise, it would lead to a deadlock
This is the wait method
Next, we need to
And there’s one more thing
Regarding this wait method
We can start writing it here.
In this app, right here.
Before we play this,
We wait for the queue to finish the tasks.
How do we call the background task completion?
It's the work that calls this method.
Before this, we constructed it here.
This created one.
Let's take a look.
Here we instantiate one, right?
So we can directly use it for waiting.
Then, we also have this queue, don't we?
Regarding this queue,
we need to make it empty.
Then we add items to it.
To be precise,
it should be set to empty.
How do we make it empty?
So, we need to create one here.
Finally, in this queue,
We just did this right before,
Our queue is named like this,
We are right here,
Let's make the naming more standardized.
Just copy this name over.
This naming is for the OPEX queue, right?
This makes it more intuitive.
Then delete this.
Then fix the error.
What is this condition?
This is a condition variable.
Regarding the condition variable,
we'll need to manage this queue later.
So let's define it first.
Then let's fix this error.
Here, we need to rename these.
Let's make some changes again
Right here
And then we wait at this spot
Before playing this
We also make sure the queue is empty
We wait for the queue to be empty
How do we wait?
We wait like this, right?
Let's copy this
The waiting queue is empty
Actually, we could write a method for this
Which queue are we waiting for to be empty?
We'll just wait for our queue, and we won't write a method for this
Let's not write a method for now
If we use it here
We can just use it directly here
If we end up using it frequently later
We can write a method for it
So, moving on here,
the lock we acquire is this lock,
we acquire this lock,
and after acquiring the lock,
we call its condition here,
this specific condition statement,
which condition variable is it?
in the app, we defined this condition earlier,
we use this condition variable to wait.
What are we waiting for?
We're waiting for this queue to be empty.
It's fine once this queue is empty.
We just need to wait for this condition to be met.
We're waiting for this queue to be empty.
When will it wake up?
Let's not get into that for now.
Let's first look at the scope of this.
Here, we're acquiring a lock.
So, this lock will only be released later, right?
Then we need to add a scope here.
Let's have a code block.
This is a new scope.
Regarding this scope,
it will release here inside.
Then let's see when it wakes up.
At this point, someone definitely needs to notify it.
Who will notify to wake up?
This is the producer.
He puts items into the queue.
It's the producer.
We should be the consumers.
When the queue is empty, we need to notify him. How do we notify him?
We still use this condition.
Here, this is the consumer.
Is he consuming here?
It will also check if it's empty.
When it's determined to be empty
we call this method here
which is to notify the producer
to inform the producer
at this point, when it's empty
it will release here
and then wake it up
after waking it up, it reacquires the lock
and then checks if it's empty again
Let's move on to the next step here.
That's how it is.
Then we'll test it again.
Uh, as mentioned in the last class, this playback two.
Will there be any noise with this two?
If there's any noise,
I'll look into whether it's a conversion issue.
Or something else.
I'll check it out later.
I'll put this audio number 2
in the notes for this class.
Just replace it with this one later.
I'll put this audio in the notes.
You can replace it later.
There's a bit of background noise.
Let's test it again.
To make sure it plays normally.
Enter the Bluetooth pairing mode.
Please use the app to connect to the Bluetooth named esp.
Three two slash three one two eight.
This two has some noise, though.
Then, you can try to adjust this.
If you don’t wake it up here,
it will stay locked here.
It waits for the lock at this point.
After it acquires the lock here,
it will go into sleep mode.
After it goes to sleep,
it will wait for the notification.
If this part is empty,
and you don’t notify it,
you can try to see if it stops here.
It plays the first audio,
which works fine,
but the subsequent audio won’t play.
You can test this out.
And this noise is an issue.
I’ll mark this as number two,
and once it’s fixed,
I’ll put it in the old notes,
at the bottom.